grants.gov 2006-06-15

# Grants.gov - Privacy and Security

Information Collected and Stored ¦  Site Security ¦  Links to Other Sites ¦  Links to Grants.gov  
Cookies ¦  Unsubscribe

Thank you for visiting Grants.gov and reviewing our privacy and security policy.

Grants.gov privacy policy protects the rights of individual users under section [552a of title 5, United States Code](http://www4.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode05/usc_sec_05_00000552---a000-.html) (commonly referred to as the 'Privacy Act', and other laws relevant to the protection of the privacy of an individual). All information is gathered, stored, and used in accordance with the above mentioned Privacy Act.

**Our privacy and security policy is clear:** _We will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us._

Here is how we handle information about your visit to our website:

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically:**  
Grants.gov does not require a user to submit information to browse the Grants.gov site. The only users who are required to submit contact information are those users who wish to be authorized submitters on behalf of their organization, or users who wish to receive information directly from Grants.gov. 

Grants.gov collects personal information about you (e.g., name, email address, phone number, title, username) only if you specifically and knowingly give it to us. If you consent to provide us with personal information (by providing feedback or by asking a question), we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. We only share the information you give us with other government agencies if your inquiry relates to that agency, or as otherwise required by law. Moreover, we do not create individual profiles with the information you provide or give it to any private organizations. We do not collect information for commercial marketing.

Grants.gov collects information to allow access for three types of users: 

  * Agency Users
  * Authorized Organization Representatives
  * Grants.gov Newsletter and Communication Notices Subscribers

All information collected and stored is in compliance with the [Paperwork Reduction Act](http://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/inforeg/prareprt.html "Paper Reduction Act"). Any information submitted to Grants.gov through the application process will be stored in the Grants.gov system for a period of six months. Additionally, no one from Grants.gov will ever ask you for personal information, such as a Social Security number, banking, or credit card information. 

When you browse, read pages or download information on Grants.gov, we automatically gather and store certain technical information about your visit. This information never identifies who you are. The information we collect and store about your visit is listed below: 

  * The Internet domain (e.g., "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our web site; 
  * The type of browser (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer) and operating system (e.g.,Windows, Unix) used to access our site; 
  * The date and time you access our site; 
  * The pages you visit; and 
  * If you linked to the Grants.gov website from another web site, the address of the website. 

This information is only used to help us make the site more useful for you. With this data we learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We never track or record information about individuals and their visits. 

Back to Top 

**Site Security**  
For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this government computer system is housed in a secure government facility and employs commercial software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload, view, change information, or otherwise cause damage.

Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Unauthorized attempts to upload, view, or change information on this site are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act. 

Back to Top 

**Links to Other Sites**  
This website has links to other websites. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site.

**Links to Grants.gov**  
The Grants.gov link is provided as a public service only. These web pages are provided as a tool to help visitors explore the wide range of options and information available, and to help them make informed choices about how to prepare for and pursue grant application opportunities. As such, the organization, services, advice, or products are not endorsed or guaranteed in any way by Grants.gov and are entirely the responsibility of the sponsor of the site visited. 

Back to Top 

**Cookies**  
To use this website, you must enable cookies support in your web browser. Cookies will only be used for the duration of the individual session to allow you easy navigation within the website. A cookie is a small piece of information that is sent to your browser-- along with a Web page-- when you access a Web site. There are two kinds of cookies. A session cookie is a line of text that is stored temporarily in your computer’s RAM. Because a session cookie is never written to a drive, it is destroyed as soon as you close your browser. A persistent cookie is a more permanent line of text that gets saved by your browser to a file on your hard drive. Depending on your browser settings, you may receive notification that a given site is requesting cookie information, possibly with an expiration date. Persistent cookies have an expiration date in the future. Session cookies have no date associated with them. 

The Grants.gov website will create a session cookie whenever you access the website. The session cookie is automatically destroyed as soon as you close your browser. We do not create any persistent cookies.

**Unsubscribe**  
If you choose to  unsubscribe from the Grants.gov Succeed Newsletter and other Grants.gov community communications and notices, visit http://www.grants.gov/EOIUnsubscribe and submit your email address. 

If you choose to  unsubscribe from Grants.gov Find Opportunity Notifications, visit http://www.grants.gov/Unsubscribe and submit your email address.

Back to Top
